This is a safe place.
What do you mean?
Just what your mum used to call it.
DYLAN: It's all over socials -
that you killed her.
It's all your fault.
and it's being taken out on me.
What you gonna do?
Get your dad to kill me?
He'll probably get his dad
to shag you.
Alana hasn't gone
to her grandparents to help them.
she's gone to get away from me.
Sarah's death is my fault.
The 24th. 25th and the 26th.
Can anyone explain
where Michael was?
Alana? I don't know!
I saw Polly in a fight
with one of the boys.
"Fight". as in handbags.
like grabbing and shoving?
This wasn't just handbags.
as you call it.
it was violent abuse.
Craig. listen to me.
do not come here. I am at work.
Please. Is that him?
I'll go and speak to him now.
He just gets so bloody angry.
Angry?
Do yourself a favour and go back...
Take your hands off me! Agh!
THEY GRUNT.
Is that what you want?
Craig. please stop.
No-one's saying he did it.
that's not what I said.
but they're asking questions.
What sort of questions?
Past behaviour.
Rory said he saw him in some
kind of fight on the rugby pitch.
I'm just telling you
what I heard. Alana.
Let's get your stuff
and come stay with me.
CLAMOURING
Agh! Agh. agh!
Dad! Dad! Alana. wait!
I haven't done anything!
Get him inside the house.
Get him inside the house. Agh!
Dad. Dad!
It's all right. it's all right.
Calm down. Agh!
Ridiculous!
I have done nothing wrong!
HANDCUFFS CLICK Agh! Oh!
You should be arresting him. not me.
Charlie-X-ray-three-five-six.
can I get an ETA
on that back-up. please?
What the hell was that?
You had your hand
around his neck. Michael.
People are gonna think
you were trying to strangle him.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
There are a few conflicting accounts
of what happened here.
What's conflicting about them?
Well. DI Stanhope says
that he came to see you.
Something about
your Tina Bradley review.
I actually asked him not to come.
Andy... Much. who's the sergeant
on duty at the house
said it looked personal.
Not something
I'm particularly comfortable about.
given your past relationship and
given you were meant to be working.
That's exactly why I said...
And that Michael Polly
came out of the house
and tried to assault him.
That's not quite what happened.
He was forced to restrain Michael.
Yes. There's also the fact
that Michael Polly
took DI Stanhope by the neck.
It was more fending him off.
Sorry. who was fending who off?
Michael was fending off Craig.
DI Stanhope.
So. he didn't put his hand
around his neck?
It's obviously relevant. Annie.
Yes.
Given how Sarah died.
It wasn't like that. Ivan.
Michael Polly is our prime suspect
in the murder of his wife.
We've spoken to DI Stanhope. and
he's decided not to press charges.
but. Annie. if an incident
such as this occurs during your time
as a family liaison officer.
we need to remove you
from that role.
You're going to remove me
from the role?
Why? What did I do?
It's standard practice.
You need to step back.
You've compromised your position.
I thought you didn't want to be FLO?
I didn't.
but he's started talking.
Men like that find it hard
to talk at the best of times.
but he's started opening up to me.
Annie... You need me in there.
I even recorded some of it.
conversations.
Well. you shouldn't have...
I'll play them for you now.
I know he's not alibied.
but I don't think he's done it.
not by the way he's talking.
Let's come back to this later.
No. Let's come back to this now. OK?
I'm the only one he'll speak to.
Why won't
this bloody thing open now?
Annie. we're not removing you
from the case.
There are still actions
to be carried out from here.
I don't want to work here.
Annie. you will do as you're told.
What?
What was your ex doing there?
Craig?
Is that who sent you the flowers?
You said to scream at you
if you ever went back.
Why didn't you tell me?
Annie...
They want me to stop as the FLO
because of what happened.
Just as he's started to talk.
they're taking it away from me.
BELL TOLLS
PAUL: You have no choice.
You need to tell the police
about the diary.
Your mum was scared.
That's what she wrote.
What if the victim wasn't your mum?
And the man you were suspicious of
wasn't your dad?
Would you go to the police then?
So the only thing stopping you
from telling the police
is the fact that it's your dad.
That is a thing. Paul.
Obviously. you love your dad.
but not to the point of letting him
get away with hurting your mum.
Alana. at the very least.
let the police work it out.
I don't know what it's about.
She just said she wanted to see us
after school.
Everyone's very excited
about the last game of the season.
and nobody's trying to look past
the events of the past few weeks.
Absolutely not.
The things that must have
been happening at home.
But we need to discuss
Dylan's academic work.
In English and biology.
he's just about on course.
but his history is...
well. we're not where we need to be.
We'd like Dylan to take a test.
to assess his progress
on Monday. after school.
That's. what. three days from now?
Push him to make an improvement
in his essay writing. otherwise...
Otherwise. we're not sure
about the rugby.
about him playing in the match.
We all want him to play.
but he's way behind in terms
of his grasp of the current module.
Rugby is Dylan's best thing.
It's how he burns off energy.
It's how he expresses himself.
Why would you do that?
It's an incentive.
No. it's just cruel.
Mrs Sedgwick.
if Dylan doesn't improve.
he'll fall behind
in terms of his predicted grades.
university choices.
This is for him.
I've spoken to Mr Whitchurch.
and he agrees.
And Mr Polly?
Mr Polly is currently suspended
from the school.
ALANA'S VOICEMAIL: 'Hello.
you've reached Alana Polly's phone.
'Please leave a message.
and I'll get back to you.'
DOORBELL RINGS
BECKY: DI Stanhope doesn't wish
to press charges.
The incident this morning. Michael.
outside. when you accosted him.
I accosted him?
Is that how you're choosing
to remember it now. yeah?
Either way.
it's not so relevant now.
as he doesn't want to press charges.
You should also know DS Cassidy
will no longer be your FLO.
DC Hammond will remain in place.
and we'll find someone
to replace Annie.
Who?
That's all to be worked out.
And what if I don't want
this person?
If it's not Annie.
I don't want anyone.
In fact. I don't want anyone here.
I'm still going to update you
whenever there's a development.
You can show yourselves out.
I just wanted to check on you.
I'm worried I got a bit heavy.
I just didn't like the way
he came charging out of that house.
I told you not to come.
I said I couldn't talk.
I know.
Thanks to you. I'm no longer FLO.
I know. And nobody
was charging anywhere. Craig.
Look. I'm sorry if I misread it.
I just didn't want him to hurt you.
Could you listen. please?
I don't want us to mess this up.
And we won't.
Annie...
I promise you.
You've made promises before.
Please.
Please just let me
book the table again
and pretend like today
never happened.
Why don't you just come over.
and I'll burn you that lasagne.
like I always used to?
You'd do that for me?
I'd do that for you.
SIREN WAILS
Alfie Lamont strangled a woman
in Leigh Woods. in 2008.
He has a history of attacking women.
One of them was a jogger.
Yeah. Annie...
Hang on. Let me just finish.
Another was a walker.
Sarah Polly was a walker.
And then he was released
from prison. 2021. and now...
We've tried that.
He lives in Abbots Leigh.
Yeah. his brother Edward does.
but Alfie Lamont's in Spain.
Is he?
Been there since February.
How do you know? We checked.
Just so you know. Annie.
we're doing all this.
We're looking at past offenders.
similar attacks. unsolved crimes.
While you were working as the FLO.
we haven't been sat here
doing nothing.
We've been working really hard.
I know how hard you work.
That bag. by the way.
Ivan says it's in the evidence room.
Bag? Bag of evidence.
PHONE RINGS It needs logging.
Stuff found at the outer cordon
of the murder site.
Ivan's asked if you could check it.
Just. you know. if you have time.
Hello? Yeah. what is it?
I'm at work.
Look. it'll have to wait
until I come home.
DOORBELL RINGS
What are you doing here?
Sir. erm. they're making me
do a history test.
I'm gonna fail it...
What's this got to do with me?
You teach history.
You're my coach. Sir.
If I fail the test.
then my season's over.
I can't play in the final match.
Shoes.
Well. they're not wrong.
You do need to improve.
But who plays in that match.
that's...
that's still my decision.
They said you were no longer
at the school. Sir.
So. what's it about. this essay?
The Munich Agreement.
Mr Bowman says
he wants an essay on Chamberlain.
The mistake of trusting Hitler.
Nobody wants an essay on why
it was a mistake to trust Hitler.
Isn't that what happened?
They certainly don't want an essay
just relaying what happened.
What they want
is to find out what you think.
They want an argument.
An argument?
Yes. pick a line.
just like in rugby.
Pick an angle.
and the harder the angle.
the more impressive it is.
So. how about this -
how about that he was right
to trust Hitler?
Was he?
Well. that doesn't matter.
That's what you claim.
What I'm trying to...
well. what Mr Bowman is trying to do
is test your ability
to make us see history differently.
In a new way. to see it in your way.
But that's not what I'm doing here.
and you need to leave.
Please. Sir.
HE SIGHS
IVAN: 'Our focus stays on one man.'
Where was Michael Polly
in the three days
before Sarah's body was found.
before we had eyes on him
at all times?
We know he left the house
on the night she went missing.
But could he have moved the body
on another night?
NIRA: Seems possible.
He's got gaps in his timeline.
knowledge of his wife's affair.
a propensity
for reacting physically.
Anything from the CCTV and
any doorbell cameras in the area?
No. footage is patchy
because it's such a rural area.
All done?
What's he...?
What's he want me to do with these?
Just logged and bagged up properly
and taken down the evidence store.
Oh.
PHONE RINGS
Hello.
CRAIG: 'Have you seen it?'
In the Mercury? The Mercury?
"Bradley family claims no new lead
in over a decade"
"as more attention is turned
to the unsolved murder"
"of a headmaster's wife."
"Brother Gareth bemoans
a lack of progress."
'Talk of "well-intentioned
detectives". and...'
Yeah. go on.
'And "never feeling
like Tina is the priority".
'Jesus.'
Is this in today's? 'Yeah.'
After everything you've done.
DOORBELL RINGS
We couldn't get hold of you.
Well. that's bollocks. for starters.
Where's Carol?
She's not in.
She's never not in. Gareth.
That's what she tells me to say
when there's someone
she doesn't wanna see.
She's got no choice. Out the way.
How did it get to this?
"Never feeling
like Tina is priority"?
Carol. I'm round here every week.
I think about her every day.
She was my friend.
When did Tina go missing? What date?
You know the date.
July 17th. 2004...
between the hours
of midnight and 1am.
It's etched on my brain. Carol.
It's a long time ago.
It's getting that way.
And I love you as a friend.
But I can't help thinking.
as a detective...
if you were gonna find her.
you'd have done it by now.
Hm?
ALARM CLOCK BEEPS
DOORBELL RINGS
MICHAEL: 'What we need
to remember is. for us.
'these events are historical.
'He didn't have the benefit
of hindsight.'
And would we think
about Chamberlain
the way that we think about him
today if we'd lost that war?
No. No. Sir.
So. what are we saying?
We're saying...
that Chamberlain was...
"Right"?
Well. we can't use that word. but...
"Unlucky"?
Yes. he was certainly that.
And maybe honourable.
because sometimes.
it's more honourable...
not to fight.
To try and find compromise and...
a peaceful solution.
When everything is pointing
towards conflict and confrontation
and the loss again
of millions of lives.
maybe the wisest
or the bravest choice
is not to engage.
And that's. erm...
an active choice in itself.
And so that can be our argument.
That's how we get you to play
in the match.
We explain the choices
that Chamberlain was facing then.
not with the benefit of hindsight.
Yes. Sir. except it's...
it's not us saying it. is it?
It's... I'm writing the essay.
Yes. that's what I meant. So...
What time's the test?
5pm. Before prep.
Well. let's make some final notes.
shall we?
DOORBELL RINGS
Dylan? Is he in there?
One of his mates said
he saw him come up here.
Dylan. out. Do you hear me?
He's helping with my history exam.
Well. he shouldn't. and he knows it.
It's totally inappropriate. Come on.
It's not inappropriate. Dylan.
Thank you. Sir. Come on.
They're getting closer
to proving it's Polly.
Apparently. his mother-in-law
reckons he did it.
I know you're not sure.
but even Alana's starting to wonder.
I can see it on her face.
Really?
You're not talking to me now?
Annie?
OK. If anyone asks. I've gone
to put this stuff in the store.
OK?
SHE SIGHS
BELL TOLLS
OK. Dylan. it's five o'clock.
Test starts now.
Do you want to get a coffee?
SHE SIGHS
One day. I'm gonna look back
on all of this...
and I'm gonna ask myself. "Did
I do the right thing for the kids?"
Saying nothing.
Doing nothing during all this shit
you've put us through.
No. I do not want to get coffee.
DOG BARKS
BARKING CONTINUES
Come on.
DOG BARKS
Can I help you? SHE GASPS.
Sorry. erm...
boring... routine check.
I'm looking for Edward Lamont.
Edward or Eddie?
If you want Eddie. you've found him.
And if I want Edward?
I don't mind waiting.
You're gonna be waiting a while.
Dad died just before Christmas.
I'm sorry. No. don't be.
All these women came out
the woodwork. all this other stuff.
In. in! Shh. shh! In. in!
You spend all your time
thinking you know a guy.
taking his word for things.
turns out he's capable of all sorts.
Do you. erm. wanna see
the death certificate? No.
I don't mind.
if it helps you with... Sorry.
In! Go. go.
CAR ENGINE STARTS
Before we tell you what we think.
I want to say well done to you.
Mr Bowman showed me your essay.
and it's clear you did a lot
of reading on the subject.
so we first want
to commend you on that.
What do you say? Thank you.
He put a lot of work in.
didn't you. mate?
It's very important to him.
playing in the rugby.
And getting better at history.
Yeah. absolutely.
That's the point of this.
We both took a look at your essay.
and there was a lot
of great work in it.
but neither of us felt that we saw
the improvement that we were after.
Chamberlain hesitated.
But I'm saying the opposite.
Failed to stand up.
But what I'm saying
is that he didn't want a war
in a "far away country".
Exactly.
We went through that in class.
A man who fails
to address his problems.
You try and make the argument
that it's honourable.
It's probably easier to argue
that it's weak or cowardly.
So does this mean I can't play
in the match?
DOOR SLAMS
25 grand a fucking year.
and for what?
Oh. fuck off!
After what you've done to her?!
My mum!
Stop it! This isn't about me!
It's not about me!
They're not punishing me!
You don't... You don't get it.
OK. they're punishing you!
I'm angry because of you!
Dylan...
Come on.
MUSIC ON RADIO: 'Back On 74'
by Jungle.
♪ Ooh. ooh. ooh. where did it go?
♪ Back on 74
♪ Call this place my home
♪ Never gonna cry any more... ♪
♪ Ooh. let it go. let it go
♪ Let it go. ooh
♪ Go? Back on 74... ♪
DOORBELL RINGS
MUSIC BLARES
Annie!
♪ Let it go. where did it all go? ♪
♪ All go? ♪
FAINTLY: Annie!
♪ Never gonna cry any more
Where did... ♪
Annie! Open the door!
MUSIC STOPS
Annie. it's me! I'm at the door!
Craig. sor...
Sorry. sorry.
I was getting a bit carried away.
Oh. there you are.
Left me standing around here
like some sort of fucking idiot.
Jesus Christ! HE BANGS ON DOOR.
Open the fucking door.
Annie... open the door.
Fuck it. I'll use my own key. then.
DOOR RATTLES
Ah. fuck. fuck!
HE BANGS ON DOOR
You can't go locking me out
of my own fucking house. Annie.
Jesus Christ.
What are you gonna do. feed me
through the fucking letterbox?
HE BANGS ON DOOR Fucking hell.
I don't know. HE BANGS ON DOOR
I thought you'd moved
beyond all this. all these games.
HE SIGHS
Annie. I have the forensics report
for the handbag.
HE SCOFFS
ECHOING: Do you wanna see it or not?
HE BANGS ON DOOR
ECHOING: Hello!
I know you can see me.
I'm doing everything right here.
To the letter.
Oh. this is bullshit.
HE BANGS ON DOOR Fuck this.
CLATTERING. GLASS SMASHES
KEYS RATTLE
HE BANGS ON DOOR. SHE EXHALES
Is that your plan - to get me
to shout at you on door camera?
I know you're there.
Look. there's the forensic report.
HE BANGS ON DOOR
I was so looking forward
to bringing it to you.
Now look what you're making me do -
breaking into my own fucking house!
HE BANGS ON DOOR
I love you.
Remember? I love you.
I hate it
when you make us fight like this.
It triggers me. You know it does.
Why would you do that?
No wonder they ended up going
to the papers.
SHE BREATHES SHAKILY
CAR DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES
CAR ENGINE STARTS
SHE BREATHES SHAKILY
BIRDS CHIRP
CLOCK TICKS
DOORBELL RINGS
She'll talk to you.
But not in the house.
ALANA: Paul says I need to go
to the police.
Says... some of that stuff
in Mum's diary
is stuff they need to be aware of.
But before we go. Dad.
I need to ask you a question.
I need you to turn around
and look me in the eye
so I can ask you the question.
And I need you to tell me the truth.
Turn around.
Dad?
Did you kill Mum?
Couldn't you have just let her go?
CAR DOOR CLOSES
I'm sorry. Sir.
but they didn't want it.
They didn't want
what you had to say.
Sorry. what does that mean?
Well. they didn't like my essay.
They didn't like the fact
that I came to you
and I asked you for help.
And you couldn't.
You didn't teach me.
Y-You messed it up.
Dylan. I'm sorry you feel like that.
but that's not...
You were teaching me for yourself.
You were thinking of yourself
when you were talking to me.
Your best player. and you still...
you fuck it up!
Don't use that word! Why?
You gonna take it out on me again?
What your wife did with my dad.
that's your fault. it's not mine!
HE SIGHS
You wouldn't pick yourself. Sir.
Because you're a pussy.
Don't use that word.
You're a pussy!
Just watch your mouth.
No. Sir! You watch my mouth!
You don't fight.
You give everyone this speech
about how everyone should
"have each other's backs".
yet you don't do shit for anyone!
No wonder people
are pointing fingers.
No wonder everyone's gone.
What are you gonna do about it?
Go on. Sir.
W-What are you gonna do to fix it?
That's what I thought.
I'm sorry.
If he makes you happy.
who am I to judge?
I'm gonna back off.
CHATTER
Guv? Guv. the daughter's here.
Wants to give us a new statement.
Here.
ALANA'S VOICEMAIL: 'Hello.
you've reached Alana Polly's phone.
'Please leave a message.
and I'll get back to you.'
PHONE RECONNECT CHIME
I wanna tell you everything.
but I want Paul to stay.
Alana. this is all on your terms.
Erm...
There'd been a lot of fighting
between Mum and Dad.
That's the first thing.
In the evenings.
er. one time after they thought
I was teaching.
but I was still in the house.
She was scared of him.
IVAN: 'You think she was scared?'
'I know she was.'
She told you?
She wrote it in her diary.
We had Mum's diary. I...
I took the pages out
because they were private.
And where are those pages now?
They burned them. her and Michael.
She's worried that she's gonna get
in trouble for that.
but I've said that she shouldn't be.
It's best to tell you everything.
That's right. Alana. Erm...
SHE SNIFFLES
Alana.
as long as you tell us the truth.
you've nothing
to be worried about. OK?
She was scared of him.
That's what it said.
And I've been thinking about it
ever since.
How... I've lived with him
all this time.
that he loves me.
But I don't really know him.
'You know. what he feels.'
NIRA: What he felt about your mum?
And what he feels about you?
About anything.
They don't... do they?
Men like that.
they tell you the practical stuff.
but they never let you in.
They can't.
Then we went to see him
this morning. didn't we?
Yeah. I wanted to ask him...
to his face.
If he killed your mum?
You asked him that?
He didn't say anything.
Subtitles by accessibility@itv.com
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm